

Julien MONTY Full Stack Web Developer

Location

Phone

Web

Email

Rieux-Volvestre, France +33 6 52 72 03 55

konpa.github.io

julien.monty@gmail.com

INTRODUCTION

Who am I.

I'm 33 and I'm a full-stack web developer based in France (Rieux-Volvestre near Toulouse). I'm specialized in Laravel PHP framework (for the back-end) and Vue.js Javascript framework (for the front-end).

My passion for web development pushes me to give the best of myself for each project, and to improve my knowledge in the field of web technologies keeping me regularly informed of the latest innovations

Since I was young, I'm interested in computers, and more generally in technologies. At 16, I started to learn web development, which has quickly grown into a passion. That's why I decided to make it my full time job after working several years for IT companies.

EXPERTISE

Domains of my expertise.



FRONT-END

I develop clear, fast and easy-to-use interfaces. My favorite frameworks are Vue.js for Javascript and Bootstrap for CSS.



BACK-END

I develop PHP applications using the MVC architecture in order to optimize their performance and maintainability. My favorite PHP framework is Laravel.



GRAPHIC DESIGN

I design for the web and for the print (flyer, logo, business card, ...). I mainly use Adobe softwares (Photoshop, Illustrator, XD).



SERVER

I install, configure and maintain Linux (Debian) web servers. I use virtualization for my development environments (Docker, Vagrant, VMWare).

LANGUAGES

My favorites languages.

85% HTML

80% PHP

70% SQL

80% CSS

75% JAVASCRIPT

65% UI/UX

I also have some experience in the following languages: Ruby, Python, LaTeX.

TOOLS

My favorites tools.

85% LARAVEL

70% WORDPRESS

65% WEBPACK

80% PHOTOSHOP

80% VUE.JS

80% GIT

75% OS (WINDOWS, OSX, LINUX)

80% ILLUSTRATOR

I also have some experience with the following tools: JQuery, Prestashop, Angular JS, Ruby On Rails, Virtualisation (Vagrant, Docker, VMWare), Amazon AWS, Visual Studio Code, Atom, Premiere Pro, After Effects.

EXPERIENCE

My professional career.

2019 - Present

AB CUBE

Full Stack Web Developer

Full remote

Development and maintenance of a pharmacovigilance web application (SafetyEasy®). Also in charge of custom developments for major clients such as L'Oréal and the ANSM (Agence nationale de sécurité du médicament et des produits de santé).

D 2016 - 2019

BEPROJECT

Full Stack Web Developer & Graphist

Mazamet, France

Development, deployment and maintenance of business web applications for pharmaceutical and automotive big companies. Team leader of a 4-5 web developers team. Installation, configuration and maintenance of server infrastructures for the web.

2015 - 2017

FREELANCE - UNPIXEL

Full Stack Web Developer & Graphist

Castres, France

Development (functional and graphic mock-up, integration, deployment, maintenance) of custom-made website or CMS for small and medium companies. Graphic creations for logos, flyers, business cards, ...

2012 - 2014

DEVOTEAM

IT Technician

Castres, France

IT support for Pierre Fabre company.

2011 - 2012

ACCENTURE

IT Technician

Dublin, Ireland

IT support for Freeport company.

2010 - 2011

HEWLETT-PACKARD

IT Coach

Rabat, Morocco

3 months mission abroad to train IT technicians on their location.

2010 - 2011

HEWLETT-PACKARD

IT Technician

IT Support / Coaching for Total company.

EDUCATION

My school cursus.

2008

CATHOLIC INSTITUTE

Law degree (not validated)

Toulouse France

First year of law degree validated at the Catholic Institute of Toulouse.

2006

HIGH SCHOOL PIERRE D'ARAGON

Scientific Baccalaureate

Muret, France

Scientific BAC option Physics-Chemistry validated with honors.

LANGUAGES

The languages I speak.

99% FRENCH

85% ENGLISH

HOBBIES

How I spend my free time.



TENNIS

I've been playing tennis in competition for 15 years and I taught tennis for 5 years to child from 5 to 17 years old.



TRAIL - HIKING

I practice trail in competition and I like to hike in nature.



PHOTOGRAPHY

I've been practicing photography for a few years. I like animal, landscape and macro photography.



VIDEO GAMES

I've been playing video games since I was a child and still today when I have some free time left.